SARATH CHANDRAN Systems Analyst (10.5+yr)

Mobile: +91 9048689200 Email: sarath.ce@gmail.com

Personal Details

Address

Ezhumavil (H) Valayanchirangara P.O Vengola, Pin:683556

Technical Skills

Technologies

ASP.NET, WinForms, WPF, WCF, Web API, MVC, Ajax, HTML, XML, Specflow, .Net Core

Languages

C#, Java, Javascript, JQuery

Database

MS SQL, MySql and MongoDb

Tools

Development Tools

Visual Studio 2019, 2017, 2015, 2012, 2010, 2008, Dev. Express and Ants Profiler

Version Control Tools SVN, VSS and Git

Project Management Tools TFS, Redmine, JIRRA

Proficiency

Win Forms & WPF

Excellent

MVC & .Net Core

Excellent

Javascript, JQuery

Very Good

SQL, MySql & Mongo DB

Very Good

IT professional with over 10.5 years of experience in software development using Microsoft .Net technologies. Having experience in desktop, web application and Web API development. Seeking a challenging job where in I can fully utilize my programming potential and my fast learning skills to contribute to the growth of organization as

ΩĐ

EDUCATION

MCA from Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam, Kerala [Institution: Nirmala College, Muvattupuzha, Eranakulam, India] [Year-2010, Percentage of Marks-72.58%]

Bsc Physics from **Mahatma Gandhi University**, Kottayam, Kerala [Institution: St. Joseph's college, Moolamattom, Kerala, India] [Year-2007, Percentage of Marks 71.33%]

Plus Two from Kerala Higher Secondary Education, Kerala, India [Institution: St:Mary's H S S, Arakulam, Kerala] [Year-2004, Percentage of Marks 67.33%]

S.S.L.C. from Board of Public Examination, Kerala, India [Institution: St:Mary's H S S, Arakulam, Kerala, India] [Year-2002, Percentage of Marks-77.66%]



EXPERIENCE

Systems Analyst in UST Global

12/2017~till date

- Involved in the initial knowledge transfer from the client and presented play back session
- Have good amount of experience in working with an agile team.
- Achieved badges and appreciations from the client and awarded reward from the company.

Team Lead in SBL Knowledge Services Ltd 10/2013~11/2017

- Worked as a team lead of 5+ team members
- Closely worked with National Informatics Center (NIC) and Govt of India officials for eVidhan project
- Involved in the CMMI Level 3 process and part of Assessment Team Member
- Achieved recognition from the company

Software Engineer in Wiltech Software Solutions 12/2010~09/2013

- Joined as a fresher and got chance to be part of many projects
- Worked as a part of many teams at the same time
- Worked as a member in a large team and as a single member



As a Developer

- Requirement collection, System study, System design, System development, System deployment and client support
- Writing unit tests and automation tests.

As a Team Lead

• Project planning, Team management, Provide Technical training to team members, Provide



1. Experian - IDaaS (Identity as a service)

Web base application which provides identity service for the individuals to prove their identity for different government services

Environment : Visual studio 2019 and Mongo DB

Technologies : MVC, .Net Core, Web API, WCF Services and Windows services

2. Seafood ERP

Seafood ERP project is a web based ERP project for sea food industry. It deals with all the functions like purchase, pre-processing, production and Inventory.

Environment : Visual studio 2012 and My SQL

Technologies : MVC and WCF Services

3. *SITCO*

SITCO is a web based application which handles all the business functions of an exporting company. It deals with the functions from lead generation to the shipment process.

Environment : Visual studio 2012 and My SQL

Technologies : MVC and WCF Services

4. <u>eLegislator HPMS (House Proceedings Management System)</u>

HPMS is a WPF application to handle house proceedings in a legislative assembly.

Client : Himachal Pradesh Vidhan sabha

Environment : Visual studio 2012 and SQL Server 2012

Technologies : WinForms, WPF, Windows Services and Web Services

5. eVidhan

This is a web based application to handle the online house proceedings of a legislative_assembly. It handles the online question processing for assembly sessions and public site for public people. Proceedings and other business related to assembly is available in this site.

Client : Himachal Pradesh Vidhan sabha

Environment: Visual studio 2012 and SQL Server 2012

Technologies : Asp.net MVC, WCF Services

6. BauBit Pro®

'BauBit Pro' is a fully integrated, platform independent, multi lingual (German, French and Italian) IT Solution for Construction companies, Landscape Architects and Allied segments. It manages the key activities of the construction company like Planning, Estimation, Work Management, Invoicing and Analysis

Client : ABBF Bausoft AG, Switzerland

Environment : Microsoft Visual C# 2012 and SQL Server 2008

Technologies : C#.Net, WinForms

7. WissSMS (School Management System)

School Management System is a fully functioned software to handle all the functionalities in a CBSE school.

Environment : Visual studio 2008 and SQL Server 2005

Technologies : C#.Net, WinForms

8. WissCare (Hospital management system for PPCC)

WissCare is a Hospital Management System for PPCC (Pain and Paliative Care Center). It handles the registration of patients, Patient Management, medicine sales and Accounts management.

Environment : Visual studio 2008 and SQL Server 2005

Technologies : C#.Net, WinForms

9. WissHMS (Hospital management system)

WissHMS is a Hospital Management System with all the functionalities for a hospital. It handles the registration of patients, Patient Management, medicine sales, IP Management etc.

Environment : Visual Studio 2008 and SQL Server 2005

Technologies : C#.Net, WinForms

10. WissIMS (Inventory management system)

WissIMS is an Inventory Management System which handles the stock management. It handles the purchase and sales of any items.

Environment : Visual studio 2008 and SQL Server 2005

Technologies : C#.Net, WinForms

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct up to my bear the responsibility for the correctness of the mentioned particulars.

Date: 12-08-2021 Place: Eranakulam

(SARATH CHANDRAN)